《艾琳》
（《How Glad I Am》 by Nancy Wilson ）
♪ My love has no beginning
♪ 我的爱没有起点
♪ My love has no end
♪ 我的爱没有尽头
♪ No front or back, and my love won't bend ♪
♪ 不前也不后 我的爱不会拐弯
♪ I'm in the middle
♪ 我在正中间
♪ Lost in a spin
♪ 迷失在旋转中
♪ Loving you...
♪ 爱你...
♪ And you don't know
♪ 你不知道
♪ You don't know, you don't know,
♪ How glad I am
♪ 我是多么高兴
♪ My love has no bottom, my love has no top ♪
♪ 我的爱没有谷底 我的爱没有顶峰
♪ My love won't rise, and my love won't drop ♪
♪ 我的爱不会上升 我的爱不会下降
♪ I'm in the middle
♪ 我在正中间
♪ And I can't stop
♪ 我无法停止
♪ Loving you...
♪ 爱你...
♪ And you don't, you don't know, you don't know ♪
♪ 你不知道
♪ You don't know how glad I am ♪
♪ 你不知道我有多高兴
♪ I wish I were a poet
♪ 我希望我是个诗人
♪ So I could express
♪ 所以我就能诗意地
♪ What I'd like to say, yeah
♪ 表达我想说的
♪ I wish I were an artist ♪
♪ 我希望我是一个艺术家
♪ So I could paint a picture
♪ 所以我就能画一副
♪ Of how I feel today, yeah
♪ 我现在心里的感觉
♪ My love has no walls on either side ♪
♪ 我的爱没有被高墙围阻
♪ That makes my love wider than wide ♪
♪ 这让我的爱更加宽广
♪ I'm in the middle
♪ 我在正中间
♪ And I can't hide
♪ 我无法隐藏
♪ Loving you...
♪ 爱你...
♪ And you don't, you don't know, you don't know ♪
♪ 你不知道
♪ You don't know how glad I am ♪
♪ 你不知道我有多高兴
♪ How glad I am
♪ 我是多么高兴
♪ How glad I am...
Eileen.
艾琳
Eileen!
I need form I-37.
我需要 I-37 表格
- Transfer form? - No.
- 转监表？- 不是
Intake. I-37.
入监表 I-37.
Aren't you listening?
你没在听吗？
She is useless.
她一点用也没有
Dr. Frye still needs to sign it.
弗莱医生还需要签字
He's probably asleep in his office.
他可能在办公室睡觉呢
Oh, yeah.
哦，是的
Maybe you could go wake up Dr. Frye.
也许你可以去叫醒弗莱医生
Blow softly in his ear.
在他耳边轻轻吹一吹
He loves that.
他喜欢这样
Leave Eileen alone.
放过艾琳吧
She's tired.
她累死了
Oh, is that what it is?
哦，是这样啊？
I thought maybe it was that time of the month.
我还以为是这个月的那个来了呢
At least I have a time of the month.
至少我每个月都还有那个来
Oh, yeah. You know something, honey?
是的 你知道吗 亲爱的？
It won't last forever. You'll be old like us soon.
不会永远都来的 你很快就会像我们一样老
Mrs. Nelson to the visiting area, please.
纳尔逊夫人请到探视区
Mrs. Nelson to the visiting area.
纳尔逊夫人前往探视区
I'm not gonna fight with anybody. I told you.
我不会和任何人打架 我告诉过你
How's Mickey doing?
米奇怎么样了？
I'm trying to be good.
我在努力做好人
Sit down. Sit down. Sit down.
坐下 坐下 坐下
Well, it's not my fault...
好吧，这不是我的错...
Maybe I'll see you next time.
下次再见吧
As much as we're gonna miss the old dog,
就像我们会想念那只老狗一样
I hope you'll all be welcoming
希望你们星期一都能
to Dr. Frye's replacement on Monday.
欢迎一下弗莱医生的继任者
A fine, fine young doctor.
一位优秀的年轻医生
Yes, well, let's hope the boys take her seriously.
是啊，希望小伙子们能认真对待她
I'll take her.
我会带上她的
- Seriously.
- 真的
I think you will be taking your insulin
我想你只要带上胰岛素
and your retirement package.
以及你的退休计划
That'll be enough for you.
就够了
That's right.
说的没错
I'll really miss all the fun around here.
我会想念这里的愉快的日子
Let's hear it for Dr. Frye.
让我们为弗莱医生鼓掌
Cheers!
干杯
I see a lot of Anne these days.
我最近经常看到安妮
Yeah, a lot of broken hearts out there.
是啊，很多人的心都碎了
Hey, hon.
嘿，亲爱的
Hey.
嘿
How's your dad?
你爸爸还好吗？
Good.
很好
You know what? Let me get that.
你知道吗？我来付那个
Thanks.
谢谢
want you to go inside and shut the fuck up!
你给我进去，闭上你的臭嘴
You shut... you shut up!
你闭嘴...你闭嘴
- Fuck off! Shut up! - You shut up!
- 滚开 闭嘴 - 你闭嘴
Fucking booze bag!
该死的酒鬼
- Oh, I'll do... I'm gonna have a drink. - You all right there, chief?
- 我会做...我要喝一杯 - 你没事吧，长官？
You can fuck right off.
你可以滚蛋了
Goddamn Lutherans next door are the problem, not me.
隔壁该死的路德教徒才有问题，不是我
Nobody's complaining. We just want to make sure
没有人投诉 我们只是想确保
you're getting home safe and sound.
你会平安回家
Nobody's complaining?
没人投诉吗？
- Dad. - Safe and sound?
- 爸爸 - 安然无恙？
Why wouldn't I be safe and sound?
我为什么不能安然无恙？
Dad.
爸爸
I keep the whole fucking neighborhood safe and sound.
我让整个街区安然无恙
- What do you know? - Dad.
- 你知道什么？- 爸爸
E-Eileen, go inside.
艾琳，进去
- Okay. Dad, look to me. - Go inside.
- 好的 爸爸 看我 - 进去吧
Come on. Please. Please.
来吧 求你了
Hey! You're causing a scene.
嘿，你在出洋相
Trust me, Eileen. Nobody wants nothing with you.
相信我 艾琳 没人想和你在一起
- Okay.
- 好的
- Come on. Go inside.
- 进去吧 进去吧
Goddamn Lutherans right there.
该死的路德会教徒
Your mother always hated those people.
你妈妈一直很讨厌那些人
- Gosh, let's go inside. - They can fuck off. Sure.
- 天哪，我们进去吧 - 他们可以滚了 当然
You can't go around policing people, Dad.
你不能到处去管人，爸爸
Who says? You know who that guy was?
谁说的？你知道那家伙是谁吗？
We got it all under control, chief.
一切都在我们掌握之中，警长
You can take it easy. Please.
你可以放轻松点 请吧
Take it easy? You fuckin' take it easy.
放轻松？你他妈的放轻松
You're not a cop anymore.
你不再是警察了
Yeah, sure.
是的，当然
I didn't want to retire. They made me,
我不想退休 他们逼我的
'cause I was too goddamn good at it.
因为我太他妈擅长这个了
- Look, I gotta get back to the station. - Pour me a drink.
- 听着，我得回局里去 - 给我倒杯酒
Good. Get back to the station, Buck.
好的 回局里去 巴克
Give me my drink.
把酒给我
Just give us a call if you need anything.
如果需要，就给我们打电话
Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
Hey, come here. What's that smell?
嘿 过来 什么味道？
Did you step in something?
你踩到什么东西了吗？
No. Why? What do you smell?
没有，怎么了？你闻到了什么？
I don't know. Roadkill.
我不知道 马路杀手
Maybe you should keep your distance.
也许你应该离我远点
Yeah, I'll keep my distance.
好 我会离你远点的
The fuck you doing? Put my fucking shoes back on.
你他妈的干什么？把我的鞋穿上
But maybe you should be nicer to me.
但也许你应该对我好一点
No one else is gonna put up with your shit.
没有其他人会忍受你的鬼话的
Go then, 'cause I got Joanie.
那就走啊，因为我还有琼妮
She wouldn't keep a place looking like this.
她可不会把房子收拾成这个样子
She's a real woman, your sister.
她是个真正的女人，你的姐姐
And she smells like a woman.
而且她闻起来像个女人
She knows how to keep a house!
她知道如何打理家务
And she doesn't live here, and she's married!
她不住在这里，而且她已经结婚了
Yeah, 'cause she's not a hanger-on.
是啊，因为她不是屌丝
And she doesn't want to talk to you!
她不想跟你说话
Yeah, sure, 'cause she's made a life of her own.
是啊，当然，因为她有自己的生活
She's made something of herself.
她已经有所成就
Whatever, Dad.
随便吧，爸爸
Get a life, Eileen. Get a clue.
过日子去吧 艾琳 找到点头绪
Shit.
妈的
Fuck it.
去他妈的
All right, listen up!
好了，听着
As you know, in the new year,
众所周知，在新的一年里
we will be up for state review.
我们将接受州里的审查
So we're gonna be tightening our procedures
因此，我们将收紧程序
and implementing new strategies based on some big, new ideas.
并根据一些重大的新想法 实施新的战略
And on that note, this new young lady to my left,
说到这，我左边这位新来的年轻女士
Dr. Miss Rebecca St. John,
博士 丽贝卡·圣约翰小姐
is our new prison psychologist.
是我们新来的监狱心理医生
She's just finished her doctorate at Radcliffe.
她刚刚完成了拉德克利夫大学的博士学位
Harvard.
哈佛大学
Ah. Harvard.
啊 哈佛
We may not be Harvard people,
我们可能不是哈佛人
but I think we can keep up with her,
但我认为我们可以跟上她的步伐
and hopefully she can keep up with us
希望她也能跟上我们的节奏
as we keep up with them.
就像我们跟上他们一样
She may be easy on the eyes, but I assure you,
她也许看起来很平易近人，但我向你保证
she is very smart.
她非常聪明
Ladies, I hope you show Miss St. John around...
女士们，我希望你们带圣约翰小姐四处转转...
Say, how much for a glazed?
甜甜圈一个多少钱？
They're free.
免费的
I'm kidding.
我开玩笑的
I'm Rebecca.
我是丽贝卡
I know.
我知道
Say, where can a girl get freshened up around here?
我说，这边哪里可以让女孩梳妆打扮一下呢？
I can show you.
我可以带你去
Sure. Appreciate it.
好的，谢谢
Can I take your jacket?
需要帮你拿外套吗？
Aren't you sweet? Thanks.
你真贴心 谢谢
This way.
这边
I don't think I caught your name.
我想我没听清你的名字
Eileen.
艾琳
- Morning. - Morning.
- 早安 - 早上好
Where you from?
你从哪里来？
Huh?
啊？
Oh, I'm from New York originally.
我来自纽约
- Manhattan.
- 曼哈顿
Couldn't stand Cambridge. Way too uptight.
受不了剑桥 太紧绷了
Well, there were a couple of interesting people,
有几个人很有意思
but, no, I needed a break.
但是，不，我需要透口气
Get some fresh air.
呼吸点新鲜空气
And I love the beach.
我喜欢海滩
All right.
好的
32...
24...
34.
Practically my measurements.
实际上是我的三围
You know, some women think their figures
你知道，有些女性认为她们的身材
are the only thing that matters.
是唯一重要的事情
Honestly, I think that's kind of pathetic.
说实话，我觉得这有点可悲
I completely agree.
我完全同意
My sister's like that, and she's not very smart.
我妹妹也是这样，而且她不太聪明
Mm, good. Then you and I
很好 那你和我就有很多
have better things to discuss than our figures.
比我们的身材更值得讨论的事情了
Although that isn't the popular opinion,
就算并不是什么流行的观点
wouldn't you say?
你说是不是？
I don't care what's popular.
我不在乎流行什么
Well, look at you.
看看你
A regular Katharine Hepburn.
一个普通的凯瑟琳·赫本
Rare to meet a young woman with so much gumption.
如此有魄力的年轻女性实属罕见
I'm like that, too.
我也是这样
I don't give a rat's ass what people think.
我才不管别人怎么想
They're probably scared of you.
他们可能是怕你
Moi?
呣啊
All right. See you around.
好的 回头见
- Every year,
- 每年
we hold this special assembly
我们都举行这个特别的大会
to celebrate the birth of Our Lord Jesus Christ.
庆祝主耶稣基督的诞生
And every year, one of you sick bastards
而每年，你们中一个变态的混蛋
ruins it for the rest of us.
都会当着其他人的面毁了它
Well, you've disrespected Christmas for the last time
那会是你们的最后一次不尊重圣诞节
because this year, you're gonna sit on your hands,
因为今年，你们要安稳坐好
you're gonna zip your lips.
闭上嘴巴
If I see any of you biting, kicking, screaming, pushing,
如果让我看到你们有人咬人 踢人 尖叫 推人
pulling hair, laughing, moaning,
扯头发 大笑 呻吟
or I hear one wayward comment,
或者我听到一句不中听的话
you're going straight to the cave.
你们就直接滚回牢房里去
And now, without further ado,
现在，话不多说
it is my honor to thank the people from Mount Olive
我很荣幸感谢奥利弗山这些
who helped me direct the pageant again this year...
今年再次帮助我指导盛会的人们
- Yay, Mount Olive. - and present to you
- 耶，奥利弗山 - 并向你们献上
"Christmas in Prison."
"狱中圣诞"
I'm gonna kill someone on Christmas.
我要在圣诞节杀个人
Shut up!
闭嘴
Oh, what am I to do?
哦，我该怎么办？
Sentenced for three years to sit indoors
我被判了三年 坐在和我一样
among boys of my same creed, plain bad.
堕落的男孩们之中，糟透了
- So much time to plot
- 有这么多时间来策划
what evildoings I'll undertake as soon as I get out.
我一出来就要做点什么坏事
You want some cake, you fatty?!
想吃蛋糕吗，胖子？
In the meantime, I suppose I could read a book.
有这时间，我想我可以读本书
You can't read, motherfucker!
你不识字，混蛋
Fucking Shakespeare up here.
该死的莎士比亚
I'm scrappy right now.
我现在很潦倒
Book of truth!
真理之书
Oh, look at McAllister.
哦，看看麦卡利斯特
- Fucking McAllister.
- 该死的麦卡利斯特
Hey, nice rack!
嘿，架子不错
Well, I'm-I'm pretty tired.
我很累了
Can we rest in that barn over there?
我们能在那边的谷仓里休息吗？
Better than paying for a motel.
总比住汽车旅馆强
You're the best, Joseph.
你是最棒的，约瑟夫
Thank you for taking us here to be counted in the census.
感谢您带我们来这里接受调查
Fuck this shit!
去他妈的
Guard!
警卫
- Wait. Wait, wait. Hey, grab him.
- 等等 等等 嘿 抓住他
Move back!
后退
All you guys sit down!
你们都坐下
Sit the fuck down!
给我坐下
Hey, Bob.
嘿，鲍勃
Hey, hon.
嘿，亲爱的
This and a pack of Luckies.
这个和一包好彩
Oh! It's a lucky day, huh?
今天真幸运，是吧？
Yeah, the luckiest.
是啊，最幸运的
Yup. Cigarettes are great.
是的 香烟是好东西
Don't light yourself on fire.
别把你自己点着了
You're in a good mood, what's wrong with you?
你心情这么好，怎么了？
Nothing's wrong, Dad.
没事 爸爸
You look funny with that thing in your mouth.
你嘴里叼着那个东西，看起来很滑稽
How was your day, Dad?
今天过得怎么样，爸爸？
How was my day?
我今天过得怎么样？
I don't know.
我不知道
It was a day, just another day.
就是一天，又一天
What's the point?
有什么意义？
My day was a doozy.
我今天过得很糟糕
Oh, yeah?
哦，是吗？
A big fight broke out at the Christmas pageant.
圣诞庆典上发生了一场大战
Kid got his collarbone broken,
小伙的锁骨断了
and I had to do all this paperwork for the warden.
我不得不为典狱长做这些文书工作
Don't ash on the floor, it's tacky.
别把烟灰搞在地板上，踩得到处都是
Anyway...
总之...
It was one of those days you never forget.
这是让人终生难忘的一天
Oh, yeah? Days I'll never forget.
哦，是吗？我永远不会忘记的日子
Let me see.
让我想想
December 16, 1944,
1944 年 12 月 16 日
first time I ever held a dead man's head in my lap.
这是我第一次把死人的头抱在腿上
What a waste.
真是可惜啊
20 degrees outside and snowing.
室外气温 20 度，正在下雪
Just like it is here.
就像这里一样
Don't know why I ever came back to this place.
我都不知道自己为什么会回到这个地方
Maybe because you had a wife and two kids.
也许是因为你有妻子和两个孩子
Maybe.
也许吧
I love the beach.
我爱海滩
Oh, yeah? Good for you.
哦，是吗？对你有好处
War kind of ruined beaches for me.
战争毁了我的海滩
So what else?
还有什么？
How's that Polk kid? He talked yet?
那个叫波尔克的孩子怎么样了？他交代了吗？
Huh?
啊？
Polk.
波尔克
The kid who stabbed his father...
刺死父亲的那个孩子
who was a good cop, more or less.
他爸一个好警察 或多或少的
What kind of kid thinks of killing his father like that?
什么样的孩子会想这样杀死自己的父亲？
Stab him in his sleep...
在他睡觉时捅他一刀...
in front of his mother.
在他母亲面前
Then he just sits down.
然后他就坐下了
Never denies it.
从不否认
Never says a word the whole trial.
在整个审判过程中一言不发
Psychopathic.
心理变态
Course I wouldn't have to worry about you
我当然不用担心你
doing something like that, now, would I?
会做出这样的事情，现在，对吧？
'Cause you're a girl.
因为你是个女孩
Can't imagine you with a knife.
无法想象你拿着刀的样子
Can you imagine me with a gun?
你能想象我拿着枪的样子吗？
Yeah, I can see it.
是的，我能想象
One day...
有一天...
when you've had enough and you feel like, uh...
当你受够了，觉得想要...
ducking out.
一了百了
Maybe when I'm dead and gone
也许等我死了以后
and you got nobody and you never will.
你谁也没有了，孤独终老
I could imagine that.
我能想象得到
But you wouldn't, would you?
但你不会的，对吧？
'Cause you're too good.
因为你太厉害了
Say, give me one of those cigarettes.
给我一支烟
What have you got, Old Gold?
你买的什么，Old Gold？
No.
不是
I like Old Gold.
我喜欢Old Gold
I know.
我知道
Oopsie.
哎呀
Do you need any help?
需要帮助吗？
Uh, no, I'm okay.
不，我没事
Just butterfingers.
就是手太滑
You should see me.
你还没看过我呢
I'm a total klutz.
我笨手笨脚的
Oh, right.
哦，对了
Lee Polk.
李·波尔克
That's not something you see every day.
这可不是每天都能看到的
Yeah, it's pretty bad.
是的，很糟糕
Bedtime reading?
睡前阅读？
I was just doing some filing.
我只是在整理文件
That's some show yesterday.
昨天的表演真精彩
They do it every year.
他们每年都这样
I'd call that cruel and unusual punishment.
我看这是很残忍和不寻常的惩罚
Sorry. I don't usually smoke.
对不起 我通常不抽烟
It's a nasty habit.
一个令人讨厌的习惯
That's why I like it.
所以我才喜欢
Not very becoming of a lady, though.
不过，这可不太淑女
Turns your teeth yellow.
会让牙齿变黄
See?
看到了吗？
That's cigarettes and coffee.
香烟和咖啡
And red wine.
还有红酒搞的
No, your teeth are perfect.
不，你的牙齿很完美
I don't drink coffee,
我不喝咖啡
so my teeth should be fine, but...
所以我的牙齿本该没问题的，但是...
they're all rotted
都烂了
due to my extreme propensity for sweets.
因为我特别爱吃甜食
A propensity for sweets.
喜欢甜食
You don't get enough sweetness in your life?
你的生活还不够甜蜜吗？
I just eat a lot of candy.
我只是吃了很多糖果
Mm. I wouldn't know it to look at you.
嗯 还真看不出来
You're so petite.
你真娇小
Being tall has its advantages, of course,
当然，个子高也有个子高的好处
but most men are just too short for me.
可是对我来说，大多数男人都太矮了
Have you noticed, or am I imagining things,
你注意到了吗，还是我在胡思乱想？
that men these days are getting shorter and shorter,
现在的男人越来越矮
balder, and fatter?
还更秃，更胖了？
All the men around here are little boys.
这里所有的男人都是小年轻
You're funny.
你真有趣
I meant outside this prison.
我是说在监狱外面
Although you're right.
虽然你说得对
The guards, the warden,
守卫们，典狱长
they're not much to look at.
真的让人看不上
You should have seen Dr. Frye.
你应该去看看弗莱医生
He was really pretty nasty looking.
他长得真的很猥琐
That doesn't surprise me.
我对此并不感到惊讶
My office isn't very becoming,
我的办公室并不宽敞
and it all smells of dirty leather.
散发着肮脏皮革的味道
I'm beginning to wonder what went on in there.
我开始怀疑里面到底发生了什么
Nothing good.
没什么好事
I mean, I never actually been in that office.
我是说，我从未真正进过那间办公室
Oh. Well, you should come by sometime.
哦 你有空应该过来看看
Although if the door's closed,
不过如果门是关着的
that means I'm with one of the boys.
说明我和其中一个男孩在
Okay.
好的
Aren't you ever scared
你难道不害怕吗？
being alone in there with them?
一个人和他们在一起？
No.
不
Come by, and see me sometime, all right?
有空来找我，好吗？
Although, you know, if you hear me screaming in there,
不过 如果你听到我在里面尖叫的话
feel free to kick down the door and rescue me.
请随时踢门救我
Okay.
好的
I'm just kidding, honey.
我开玩笑的，亲爱的
There's a buzzer.
有警报器的
I'm here to see Leonard Polk.
我是来见伦纳德·波尔克的
Anne Polk.
安妮·波尔克
You're not on the schedule.
你不在日程表上
Are you a late addition?
你是最近才预约的吗？
I was called.
我是被叫来的
I don't know, I-I'm here now.
我不知道，我现在就在这里
Well, you need to fill out a form.
你需要填写一份表格
Aren't you Chief Dunlop's kid?
你不是邓洛普警长的孩子吗？
Yeah.
是啊
I thought so.
我想也是
Mrs. Polk? I'm Dr. St. John.
波尔克夫人？我是圣约翰医生
We spoke on the phone. Thank you so much for coming.
我们通过电话 非常感谢你能来
Oh, no need to bother with that.
哦，没必要这么麻烦
We all know who you are.
我们都知道你是谁
Eileen, would you help us with the door?
艾琳，你能帮我们开门吗？
Thank you.
谢谢
- It's this way.
- 这边走
Take your coat?
拿上你的外套？
Please.
请
Thank you, Eileen.
谢谢你，艾琳
After you.
你先请
Why are you doing this to me?
你为什么要这样对我？
Huh?
啊？
You got something to say to me?
你有话要跟我说吗？
Let me out!
让我出去
Let me out! Let me out!
让我出去 让我出去
Let me out!
让我出去
Y-You do... y'all do what you want with him.
你们...你们想怎么处置就怎么处置吧
Won't even talk to his own mother?
连和自己的母亲都不肯说一句？
He's always been a nasty boy.
他一直是个讨厌的孩子
A filthy, nasty boy!
一个肮脏讨厌的孩子
I need to lock up.
我要锁门了
Visitation hours were actually over 20 minutes ago.
实际上，探视时间已经超了20分钟
Oh, I-I understand.
哦，我明白了
Would you like to keep talking in my office?
你想到我的办公室里继续聊聊吗？
- Let's go. - Turn around.
- 我们走 - 转过去
Oh, no. That won't be necessary.
哦 不用了 没这个必要
- I need to cuff him. - No.
- 我得把他铐起来 - 不
Don't worry, Lee. It's all right.
别担心 李 没事的
That won't be necessary.
没有这个必要
Don't do that. She's a doctor.
别这样 她是个医生
I think she needs a doctor.
我觉得她需要看医生
That kid killed a cop.
那孩子杀了警察
He killed his father.
他杀死了他的父亲
There's a difference.
不一样的
Oh, I'm so sorry. Let me see who it is.
哦 真对不起 让我看看是谁
Oh, Eileen.
哦，艾琳
Um, can I help you?
有什么能帮您的吗？
You forgot your notebook.
你忘带笔记本了
Oh, thank you so much.
哦，太谢谢你了
I actually need this.
我真的需要这个
Um, hope you didn't read it.
嗯，希望你没读过
- No, of course not. - Oh, no,
- 不，当然不是 - 当然没有
I'm just kidding. It's just chicken scratch.
我开玩笑的 只是胡乱划了几笔
Wait. Eileen.
等等 艾琳
I don't mean to be forward,
我并不是想太强势
and, um, you probably have other plans already,
而且，嗯，你可能已经有其他计划了
but, um, can I take you to a drink tonight?
不过，今晚我能请你喝一杯吗？
I don't know anyone in this darn town,
我在这该死的镇子里一个人都不认识
and I'd love to treat you to a cocktail if you're game.
如果你愿意，我很乐意请你喝鸡尾酒
- Okay. - Okay?
- 好的 - 好的
- I've twisted your arm?
- 不会太为难吧？
So, uh, who makes the best martini in town?
那么，哪家的马提尼最好喝？
- Maybe O'Hara's? - O'Hara's.
- 也许是奥哈拉酒吧？ - 奥哈拉酒吧？
It's actually the only bar in town.
实际上，这是镇上唯一一家酒吧
No, O'Hara's is good.
好，奥哈拉酒吧就可以
See you at 7:00?
7 点见？
With bells on? Is that the expression?
准点见？是这么说吗？
♪ I know you've been hurt
♪ 我知道你受伤了
Ah!
啊
♪ By someone else
♪ 为某个人
♪ I can tell by the way
♪ 我可以感觉到
♪ You carry yourself
♪ 从你的一举一动
♪ But if you let me
♪ 但如果你允许
♪ Here's what I'll do
♪ 我会这么做
♪ I'll take care of you
♪ 我会照顾你
♪ I... I've loved and lost
♪ 我也爱过迷失过
♪ The same as you
♪ 和你一样
♪ So you see, I know
♪ 所以你看，我明白
♪ Just what you've been through ♪
♪ 你正在经历的一切
♪ But if you'll let me
♪ 但如果你允许
♪ Here's what I'll do
♪ 我会这么做
♪ Oh, I just got to take care of you ♪
♪ 我会照顾你
♪ You won't ever have to worry ♪
♪ 你再不用担心
♪ You won't ever have to cry
♪ 你再也不会要哭泣
♪ For I'll be there beside you ♪
♪ 因为我会在你身边
♪ To dry your weeping eyes
♪ 擦干你哭泣的双眼
♪ So, darling
♪ 亲爱的
♪ Tell me
♪ 告诉我
♪ That you'll be true
♪ 你是真心的
♪ For there is no doubt...
♪ 因为那不用怀疑
- Hi. - Oh, Eileen.
- 嗨 - 艾琳
Hi.
你好
Please, please, please, sit.
请坐下
Um, what are you having?
你要喝什么？
Uh, I'll have a beer, I guess.
呃，我想我还是喝啤酒吧
A beer? Oh.
啤酒？哦
Hi, Eileen.
嗨，艾琳
Good to see you, hon.
很高兴见到你，亲爱的
What's next, sweetheart?
来点什么，亲爱的？
Um, well... Oh, my stars.
嗯...我的天啊
You're absolutely frozen.
你绝对冻僵了
Um, one beer, please, and maybe a little whiskey
请给我一杯啤酒，也许再来点威士忌
to warm up my girl. What say, huh?
温暖温暖我的女孩 怎么样？
My, you look very glamorous.
天哪，你看起来真迷人
It's just an old dress.
这只是一件旧衣服
May I?
可以吗？
How about you, sweetheart? Another martini?
你呢，亲爱的？再来杯马提尼？
Love one. Thank you.
来一个 谢谢
Maybe let's hold the olives this time.
也许这次我们可能要多喝两杯
I thought I'd have a hard time finding this place,
我本以为这个地方很难找
but here it is.
但也不难嘛
You feeling all right?
你还好吗？
Yeah, I'm fine.
我没事
Uh, there's something wrong with my car,
我的车有点问题
so I have to drive with the windows down,
所以我必须开着窗开车
or else it fills with smoke.
否则就会烟雾弥漫
- Oh, you're kidding.
- 哦，开玩笑
That sounds absolutely awful.
这听起来太可怕了
Can't you get your husband to fix that for you?
你就不能让你丈夫帮你修好吗？
Oh, no, I'm not married.
哦，不，我还没结婚
I've always been single.
我一直都是单身
And when I do have a guy around,
当我身边有男人的时候
it's just for fun, and it's brief.
只是为了好玩，从不长久
No, I never stay anywhere long with anything.
不，我从不在一个地方为任何人驻足
Sort of my modus vivendi
我的生活方式
or my pathology, depending on who I'm talking to.
或我的病态，要看是在跟谁聊了
How long have you worked at Moorehead?
你在摩尔黑德工作多久了？
Three or four years.
三四年
Uh, it was only supposed to be temporary,
呃，本来只是暂时的
while I moved back for a bit while my mother was sick,
母亲生病期间，我搬回来住了一段时间
and then she died, so...
然后她去世了，所以
I've been at the prison, and time's just flown by.
我就一直在监狱，时间过得飞快
Oh, God.
哦，上帝啊
Prison is no place for time to fly by.
监狱可不是时光飞逝的地方
And your mother dying.
还有你母亲的去世
That's a lot for a young lady.
对一位年轻女士来说，这已经够多了
Ah. 24.
啊 24岁
Then you must be eager to get back out there. Are you?
那你一定很想再出去走走 是吗？
You know, um, I'm an orphan, too.
你知道，嗯，我也是个孤儿
My uncle raised me out West.
我叔叔在西部把我抚养长大
Where the sun shines.
阳光普照的地方
I don't understand how you all do it here,
我不明白你们是怎么做到的
winter after winter.
一个冬天又一个冬天
It's positively creepy. I don't know.
真的是冻死人了 我也不知道
I'm in a sort of strange love affair with New England.
我对新英格兰有着一种奇怪的情结
I love it, but I also hate it.
我喜欢它，但也讨厌它
Things feel very real here, don't they?
这里的一切都很真实，不是吗？
Sort of there's no...
算是没有...
imagination.
想象力
There's no sentimentality or fantasy.
没有感伤，也没有幻想
There's... there's just nowhere to hide.
这里...这里无处可藏
Sorry.
对不起
I've had too much to drink.
我喝多了
I tend to talk when I've had too much to drink.
我一喝多就爱说话
It's all right.
没事的
Mm, it's better than talking too little.
嗯，总比不说话要好
Did you see Lee Polk today?
你今天看到李·波尔克了吗？
Uh...
呃...
Did she say anything to you?
她跟你说什么了吗？
Mrs. Polk?
波尔克夫人？
She was just upset.
她只是心烦意乱
Those mothers are always upset.
那些母亲总是不高兴
Mm-hmm.
嗯
Did she seem like an angry woman to you?
你觉得她是个愤怒的女人吗？
I don't know. Uh...
我不知道呃...
everyone's kind of angry here.
大家都很生气
- It's Massachusetts. - Mm.
- 这里是马萨诸塞 - 嗯
Well, I had this professor at Harvard.
我在哈佛有个教授
He was brilliant, but very difficult.
他才华横溢，但非常难相处
Uh, he did this... these experiments on prisoners
呃，他在囚犯身上做了这些
studying the effects of psychedelics on recidivism.
研究迷幻药对累犯的影响的实验
Now, I don't agree with his methods,
我不同意他的方法
there is no magic pill,
世上没有灵丹妙药
but... but you can set people free...
但是...但是你可以给人们带来自由...
if you can get them to tell the truth, to feel it.
如果你能让他们说出真相，感受到真相
That's what I want to do.
这就是我想做的
Secrets and lies.
秘密与谎言
I tell you, doll...
我告诉你，娃娃...
some families are so sick, so twisted,
有些家庭太变态了，太扭曲了
the only way out's for someone to die.
唯一的出路就是有人死掉
Don't you think?
你觉得呢？
Hey! What'd you say your name was?
你说你叫什么名字？
Who, me?
谁？
Ah, yeah. W-We was just saying
是啊 我们刚才正在聊
that you look so familiar.
你看起来这么熟悉
Are you in the movies or something?
你拍过电影吗？
Hardly. I work at the boys' prison.
很难说 我在男子监狱工作
- I'm Eileen,
- 我是艾琳
and this is my friend, Rebecca.
这是我的朋友丽贝卡
She's a psychologist.
她是个心理医生
Don't be shy, Rebecca.
别害羞 丽贝卡
These boys won't bite.
这些孩子不会咬人
Not unless you ask us to.
除非你要求我们这样做
This is Jerry. You can ignore him.
这是杰瑞 你可以无视他
He's married.
他结婚了
What happened to your teeth, Jerry?
你的牙齿怎么了，杰瑞？
You get into a fight with your old lady?
你和你老婆吵架了？
That's it. His wife's got a left like Joe Frazier.
就是这样 他老婆的左手和乔·弗雷泽一样壮
Nah, nah. He... he slipped on the ice.
不 不 他...他在冰上滑倒了
I'm gonna grow some new ones, though.
不过，我会再种几颗新的
Mm-hmm.
嗯
Just need a few more of these.
只要再多来几杯这个
Cheers to that. To Jerry and his new teeth.
干杯 为杰瑞和他的新牙干杯
Hey.
嘿
♪ You've gotta want it bad
♪ 你一定很想要
♪ If that guy's got into your blood ♪
♪ 如果那家伙进了你的心里面
Feel like dancing, Rebecca?
想跳舞吗，丽贝卡？
With you?
和你？
Yeah.
是啊
♪ The very heart of you
♪ 你的内心
♪ Makes you want to breathe
♪ 让你想呼吸
♪ Here's the thing to do
♪ 现在有件事要做
♪ Tell him that you're never gonna leave him
♪ 告诉他你永远不会离开他
♪ Tell him that you're always gonna love him
♪ 告诉他你永远爱他
♪ Tell him, tell him, tell him, tell him right now
♪ 告诉他, 告诉他, 现在就告诉他
♪ I know something about love
♪ 我对爱有所了解
♪ You gotta show it and
♪ 你必须表现出来
♪ Make him see the moon up above
♪ 让他看到天上的月亮
♪ Out and get him, Do, do do
♪ 出去抓住他
♪ If you want him to be always by your side
♪ 如果你想让他永远陪在你身边
♪ If you want him to only think of you
♪ 如果你想让他心里只有你
♪ Tell him that you're never gonna leave him
♪ 告诉他你永远不会离开他
♪ Tell him that you're always gonna love him
♪ 告诉他你会永远的爱他
♪ Tell him, tell him, tell him, tell him right now
♪ 告诉他, 告诉他, 现在就告诉他
♪ Ever since the world began
♪ 自从有了这世界
♪ It's been that way for man
♪ 这就是我们 男人
♪ And women...
♪ 和女人...
♪ The touch of your lips
♪ 轻轻吻在你唇上
♪ Next to mine
♪ 我的唇
♪ Gets me excited
♪ 让我好兴奋
- ♪ Makes me feel fine - No.
- ♪ 让我感觉很好 - 不
♪ The touch of your hand
♪ 轻轻抚过你的手
♪ Your sweet hello
♪ 你甜蜜的问候
♪ The fire inside you
♪ 你内心的火焰
♪ When you're holding me close
♪ 当你紧紧抱着我
♪ Your love so warm and tender
♪ 你的爱温暖又温柔
♪ The thrill is so divine
♪ 那心动的感觉如此神圣
♪ It is all these things
♪ 就是这些事情
♪ That make you mine
♪ 让你成了我的人
♪ If you would leave
♪ 如果你要离开
♪ I surely would die
♪ 我一定会死
♪ When you were ten minutes late ♪
♪ 当你迟到十分钟
♪ I started to cry
♪ 我开始哭泣
♪ Ah, ah, ah
♪ 啊
♪ I've got it bad
♪ 我陷得这么深
♪ But it's all right
♪ 不过没关系
♪ As long as you're here
♪ 只要你在这里
♪ Every night...
♪ 每天晚上...
You remind me of a girl in a Dutch painting.
你让我想起了荷兰油画中的一个女孩
You have a strange face.
你有一张奇怪的脸
It's plain, but...
普通，但...
fascinating.
迷死人
It has a beautiful...
有一股美丽的...
turbulence.
湍流
I love it.
我喜欢
I bet you have brilliant dreams.
我敢打赌，你的梦想一定很美好
I bet you dream of other worlds.
我敢打赌，你一定梦见过其他世界
Maybe you'll dream of me and my morning remorse,
也许你会梦见我和我清晨的懊悔
which is certain.
这是肯定的
I shouldn't drink,
我不该喝酒
but I do.
但我喝了
Thank you.
谢谢
Hey, Sandy, can I get a martini and some matches?
嘿，桑迪，能给我一杯马提尼酒和火柴吗？
Better be careful, Eileen.
最好小心点 艾琳
I don't want any trouble with your dad.
我不想你爸爸来找麻烦
My dad's not gonna cause any trouble.
我爸不会找你麻烦的
Dad. Dad.
爸爸 爸爸
Dad, can you let me in?
爸爸，能让我进去吗？
Shit.
妈的
Hey, Dad!
嘿，爸爸
Can I have the keys?
能把钥匙给我吗？
Can I please have the keys?
能请你把钥匙给我吗？
No, you may not have the keys.
不行，不能给你钥匙
Not until you read that book from cover to cover.
除非你从头到尾读完这本书
I want to hear every word.
一字不漏的
Where'd you put the keys?
你把钥匙放哪儿了？
Make yourself comfortable, Eileen.
请随意 艾琳
You're not going anywhere till you read the last word.
在读完最后一个字之前，你哪儿也别想去
Dad, this is ridiculous. I need to go to work.
爸爸 这太荒唐了 我得去上班了
Out all night.
整夜不归
Nearly crashed the car.
差点撞车
Sleeping in your own sick,
睡在自己的病床上
and now you're worried about getting to work on time?
现在你开始担心不能准时上班了？
I can hardly look at you, I'm so ashamed.
我都没眼看你，太丢人了
Oliver Twist would be grateful for this home,
奥利弗·忒斯特会对这个家感激不尽
but you, Eileen,
但是你，艾琳
you're trash, Eileen, just trash.
你是垃圾，艾琳，就是垃圾
All I did was go out with a girl from work.
我不过就是和一个女同事去聚了个会
You went out with a girl from work?
你和一个女同事聚会了？
Do I look like I was born yesterday?
我看起来像昨天才出生的吗？
Who is he? Huh?
他是谁？
Who is this boy? I just want to know who he is
这个男孩是谁？我只想知道他是谁
before you get knocked up and sell your soul to Satan.
在你怀孕并把灵魂出卖给撒旦之前
Can you just give me the keys?
你能把钥匙给我吗？
Please! I'll be late!
求你了 我要迟到了
You're not going anywhere dressed like that.
你穿成这样哪儿也去不了
I mean, really, Eileen, how dare you?
我的意思是，真的，艾琳，你怎么敢的？
That's the dress your mother wore to my father's funeral.
那是你母亲在爷爷葬礼上穿的衣服
You got no respect for anyone.
你不尊重任何人
Get changed.
赶紧换了
I don't want anyone seeing you in that getup.
我不想让任何人看到你穿成这样
They'll think I'm dead.
他们会以为我死了
Ah. Miss Dunlop?
邓洛普小姐？
May I, um, may I have a word?
我能说句话吗？
Oh, Jesus.
天啊
It's about your father.
是关于你父亲的
Him? Go talk to him. He's inside.
他？去和他谈谈 他在里面
It's about his gun.
是关于他的枪
This oughta be good.
应该没事
Pray tell, Buck.
请告诉我 巴克
Uh, yesterday,
呃，昨天
we got several complaints from neighbors,
我们收到了几位邻居的投诉
from Miss Connie down at the school,
据学校的康妮小姐所说
that, uh, Chief Dunlop
邓洛普警长
was sitting in that north-facing window
坐在朝北的窗前
and, uh, pointing his weapon
用武器指着
to children walking home from school.
放学回家的孩子们
He has agreed to relinquish the property into your care.
他已同意将枪支交由您照管
As long as you promise not to use it on him.
只要你保证不会拿来用在他身上
His words.
他的话
May I come in?
我可以进去吗？
Want to hang it on me like an ornament?
想把那玩意像装饰品一样挂在我身上吗？
I'm sure that Miss Dunlop
我相信邓洛普小姐
will take excellent care of the weapon, sir.
会好好保管武器的，长官
As she does with all things, Buck, as you can see.
就像她对所有事情的态度一样，巴克，你也看到了
♪ It's Christmastime
♪ 圣诞节到了
♪ And I wanna see Santa Claus
♪ 我想见圣诞老人
♪ What? What? What?
♪ 什么 什么 什么
♪ Yes, it's Christmastime
♪ 是的，现在是圣诞节
♪ And I wanna see Santa Claus
♪ 我想见圣诞老人
♪ What? What? What?
♪ 什么 什么 什么
♪ Gonna ask him for my baby
♪ 我要向他要我的孩子
♪ Ain't that a real good cause?
♪ 难道这不是一个真正的好理由
Let me know which ones.
让我知道是哪些
Sure. I'll hold.
好的，我等着
Ah, look what the cat dragged in.
啊，看那只猫叼来了什么？
- Good afternoon, Eileen.
- 下午好，艾琳
You look fresh as a daisy, as always.
你看起来像雏菊一样鲜艳，一如既往
I had car trouble.
我的车出了问题
Yeah, I believe the trouble part.
是的，我相信有问题
It's almost Christmas. Can you give me a break?
都快圣诞节了 你能放我一马吗？
No. Get to work.
不，赶紧去工作
Okay. I need the Polk file.
好的 我需要波尔克的文件
- Yeah.
- 是啊
I think Dr. St. John has it.
我估计圣约翰医生拿着呢
Perfect. Yeah, I'm afraid that one
好极了 是的 恐怕那个
will have to wait till after the holidays.
只能等到假期结束后了
We have a new doctor on staff,
我们新来了一位医生
and, uh, apparently she doesn't follow procedures.
显然她不遵守程序
- She's not in today? - Been and gone.
- 她今天没来？- 已经走了
She's gonna be back after Christmas.
她圣诞节后才会回来
Yeah. Will do.
好的 好的
All right, then. Thank you.
那好吧 谢谢
Bye-bye.
再见
Where do you think you're going?
你想去哪儿？
The infirmary.
医务室
I think something's going around.
我觉得有些事情正在发生
You look like you've been going around.
看起来好像你才有事
She's a boozer.
她是个酒鬼
Dad?
爸爸？
- Dad, can you hear me?
- 爸爸，你能听到我吗？
Dad, can you hear me?
爸爸，你能听到我吗？
- What were you doing up there? - I need my gun.
- 你在上面干什么？- 我需要我的枪
- Sit up. - It's after me.
- 坐起来 - 它在追我
Nobody's after you.
没人追杀你
Sit up. Sit up.
坐起来 坐起来
Joanie.
琼妮
That you, Joanie?
是你吗，琼妮？
Hey.
嘿
Joanie. Joanie.
琼妮 琼妮
Joanie.
琼妮
Dad.
爸爸
Quit your fussing, Joanie.
别大惊小怪的，琼妮
We stitched him up,
我们给他缝合了伤口
and I don't think he has a concussion,
我不认为他有脑震荡
but his blood alcohol level
但他血液中的酒精含量
is point one-seven.
是 1-7 点
His liver's enlarged, and he's covered in bruises.
他的肝脏肿大，浑身是伤
I'm not blaming you, honey, but, uh...
我不是责怪你，亲爱的，但是...
Yeah, sure.
是的，当然
Hey, who's letting him live like this?
嘿，是谁让他这样生活的？
I don't know. My mom died, and he doesn't have a job.
我不知道 我妈妈去世了 他也没有工作
What else is he supposed to do?
他还能做什么？
Yeah, there are men who don't drink all day.
是的，也有些男人不会整天喝酒的
I know that.
我知道
Look, I know this is hard for you, but, uh...
听着，我知道这对你来说很难，但是...
if he stops drinking, he might die,
如果他不喝酒，可能会死
but if he keeps drinking, it'll definitely kill him.
但如果他继续喝下去，肯定会要了他的命的
I don't know what else to say to you.
我不知道还能对你说什么
Sit down, Dad.
坐下 爸爸
The doctor told me you're gonna die.
医生说你快死了
Oh, like he's not?
哦，好像他不会死似的
He said, if you keep drinking like this,
他说，如果你继续这样喝下去
it'll kill you.
会害死你的
Screw him.
去他的
You know they killed your mother at that hospital.
你知道他们那家医院害死了你母亲
They owe me more than stitches.
他们欠我的不是缝几针就完了的
Can you lean back?
你能往后靠吗？
Course I can lean back.
我当然可以往后靠
You don't think I know how to go to bed?
你以为我不知道怎么上床睡觉吗？
Well, I need a drink.
我要喝一杯
Dad!
爸爸
And anyway, I do not sleep here.
总之，我不要在这睡
- It's haunted. - Please, Dad.
- 这闹鬼 - 求你了，爸爸
If I get you a bottle, will you lie down?
如果我给你拿一瓶，你会躺下吗？
No. I want to have a drink with my daughter.
不，我想和我女儿喝一杯
You're different these days.
这些天你变了
You're almost interesting.
你有趣多了
What are you doing with all the money you make at work?
你工作赚来的钱花哪里去了？
Why don't you ever buy your own clothes?
你为什么不给自己买点衣服？
I remember that coat.
我记得那件大衣
I remember your mother...
我记得你的母亲...
How does it look on me?
我穿起来怎么样？
Well, your mother looked beautiful in that coat.
你妈妈穿那件大衣真漂亮
I bought it for her to wear
我买给她
when she got out of the bughouse.
出院的时候穿的
I always loved your mother.
我一直很爱你的母亲
No matter what you thought it looked like,
不管你觉得这看起来像什么样子
I always loved her.
我一直很爱她
And I know what people say about me.
我知道人们是怎么说我的
They say I made her crazy 'cause I'm a hard-ass.
他们说是我把她逼疯的，因为我是个硬茬子
And I may have yelled a few times,
我可能还大喊了几次
but she always forgave me.
但她总是会原谅我
Because we loved each other.
因为我们彼此相爱
Love will make you crazy, Eileen.
爱会让你疯狂 艾琳
You'll probably never understand that.
你可能永远都不会明白
Why?
为什么？
Some people...
有些人...
they're the real people.
他们才是真正的人
Like in a movie, they're the ones you're watching.
就像电影一样，你看到的就是他们
They're the ones making moves.
他们在行动
And the other people...
而其他人...
they're just there filling the space,
他们只是在那里滥竽充数
and you take 'em for granted.
而你却认为这是理所当然的
You think, "They're easy."
你觉得 "这谁不会啊"
Take a penny, leave a penny.
挣点钱，花点钱
That's you, Eileen.
这就是你，艾琳
You're one of them.
你就是其中之一
What are you doing? You don't gotta lock it.
你在干什么？不用锁门
- Let's go.
- 我们走吧
- Come on. Come on.
- 来吧 来吧
Come on. It's cold out here.
来吧 外面很冷
Come on. Hurry up.
快点 快点
Open the door.
开门
Fucking heavy.
真他妈重
Give me my fucking drink.
把他妈的酒给我
Eileen!
艾琳
What, Dad?
什么，爸爸？
Phone rang.
电话响了
Some woman looking for you.
有个女人在找你
What'd you say?
你说什么？
Nothing.
什么都没有
I know nothing. I said nothing.
我什么都不知道 我什么也没说
Hello.
你好
Hello, Christmas angel.
你好，圣诞天使
Rebecca?
丽贝卡？
Look, I was just thinking of you,
听着，我只是在想你
and, well, I-I don't know
我不知道
what you're planning for Christmas Eve,
你平安夜有什么计划
but I thought maybe you'd like to come over.
但我想也许你愿意过来
There are some records we could play,
我们可以播放一些唱片
and maybe dance again if all goes well.
如果一切顺利，也许还能再跳一次舞
Unless you have a better offer, of course.
当然，除非你有更好的提议
I don't have a better offer.
我没有更好的提议
- So you'll come? - Yeah.
- 那你会来吗？- 好啊
Let me give you the address.
让我把地址告诉你
Okay. Hold on.
好的 等一下
It's 32 Maple Street.
枫树街 32 号
So see you later.
再见
- Bye. - Bye.
- 再见 - 再见
♪ The touch of your lips
♪ 轻轻吻在你唇上
♪ Next to mine
♪ 我的唇
♪ Gets me excited
♪ 让我好兴奋
♪ Makes me feel fine
♪ 让我感觉很好
♪ The touch of your hand
♪ 轻轻抚过你的手
♪ Your sweet hello
♪ 你甜蜜的问候
♪ The fire inside you
♪ 你内心的火焰
♪ When you're holding me close ♪
♪ 当你紧紧抱着我
♪ Your love so warm
♪ 你的爱温暖
♪ And tender...
♪ 又温柔...
♪ Once I had
♪ 我曾经
♪ A secret love
♪ 暗恋过
♪ That lived
♪ 深藏在
♪ Within the heart of me
♪ 我的内心里
♪ All too soon
♪ 太快了
♪ My secret love
♪ 我的暗恋
♪ Became...
♪ 成为...
- Oh!
- 哦
Y-You're here.
你来了
- It's a Christmas miracle.
- 这是一个圣诞奇迹
Sorry it took me so long.
抱歉，我花了这么长时间
I think that cat's possessed.
我觉得那只猫中邪了
Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
Oh. Aren't you a peach?
哦 你真是个甜心啊？
Come in! Come in.
请进 进来吧
Eileen, um,
艾琳
I'm sorry the place is such a mess.
我很抱歉这里一团糟
I-I haven't... I mean, I tried to clean it up a bit,
我没有...我是说，我试着清理了一下
- but it's just beyond me.
- 但我实在搞不定
I hope it doesn't make you uncomfortable.
我希望这不会让你感到不舒服
Let's open this wine.
让我们开了这瓶酒
Uh, sit down. Sit down. Sit down.
呃 坐下 坐下
♪ Just how wonderful you are...
♪ 你是多么美好
I hope you didn't have to drive far. Was it far?
我希望你没有开很远 远不远？
Uh, no. I drive all over the place.
不远 我开车到处跑
Let me take your coat.
我帮你拿外套
- Thanks. - Oh, my.
- 谢谢 - 哦，天哪
It's so nice and soft.
又漂亮又柔软
It's my mother's.
这是我妈妈的
Well, uh, she must have been a real classy lady
她一定是个非常优雅的女士
to have such a classy daughter.
有一个如此优雅的女儿
She was something of a clotheshorse, actually.
事实上，她是个衣架子
- I hope it's a kind you like.
- 希望是你喜欢喝的那种
Oh. I'm sure it's delicious.
哦 一定很好喝
Drink sounds nice, actually.
事实上，喝酒听起来不错
Let's see where the corkscrew's hiding.
让我们看看开瓶器藏在哪里
- Uh, you know,
- 你知道
I have just been so busy lately
我最近太忙了
that I can't seem to remember where the...
我似乎记不起在哪里...
But it's got to be here under all this mess, right?
但它一定就在这些乱七八糟的东西下面，对吗？
You know what?
你知道吗？
A very handy young PhD student once taught me a trick
一位心灵手巧的年轻博士生曾经教过我一招
for how to open a bottle if you're ever stranded
如何打开一个酒瓶 如果你
without a corkscrew.
没有开瓶器的话
Philosophers are always the biggest drunks.
哲学家一直是最大的酒鬼
Although he was kind of cute.
虽然他有点可爱
Eugene Henderson, Harvard.
尤金·亨德森，哈佛大学
I had no idea you could do that.
我不知道你还能这么做
That was a great trick.
这一招真不错
Mm-hmm.
嗯
Now we need some glasses.
现在我们需要一些酒杯
Ah.
啊
So to Eileen, my Christmas savior.
艾琳，我的圣诞救星
Savior?
救星？
I didn't do anything.
我什么都没做
Well, you're being a friend.
好吧，你是一个朋友
That's everything. Cheers.
这就是一切 干杯
♪ A love I thought would last for a lifetime...
♪ 我以为会持续一生的爱...
God, that's awful.
天哪，太难喝了
No. That's a...
不，就是...
punch of flavor.
这股味道
That's what a Syrah is.
西拉葡萄酒就这味
Hope you haven't spent too much on it.
希望你没花太多钱
To...
敬...
To Jesus Christ.
敬耶稣基督
Happy birthday.
生日快乐
Mmm.
嗯
Do you live here alone?
你一个人住在这里吗？
No.
不
Oh, uh, sure.
哦，当然
I, uh... No, I can't have roommates.
我...不，我不能有室友
I, um, I like my own space.
我喜欢自己的空间
I still like to have fun,
我还是喜欢找乐子
and, uh, I can make a lot of noise.
而且，我可能还会很吵
And, uh, I can make a mess, as you can see,
而且，你也看到了，我搞得一团糟
but, uh, I can play music as loud as I want to.
但是，我想放多大声就放多大声
I can...
我可以...
I can scream as loud as I want to.
我可以尽情尖叫
I can't stand roommates, either.
我也受不了室友
In college, I had to lock my door...
在大学里，我不得不把门锁上...
Oh, that's right. You were in college.
对了 你上过大学
What'd you study?
你学的什么？
Just the required courses.
只是些必修课
Um, if I hadn't left,
嗯，如果我没有离开
I probably would have ended up a secretary anyway.
最终我可能都会成为一名秘书
Eileen, you're not really a secretary.
艾琳，你不是一个真正的秘书
Mrs. Murray and Mrs. Stevens, they're secretaries,
默里太太和史蒂文斯太太 她们是秘书
'cause they do what they're told,
因为她们听命行事
and that's why they're miserable and nasty.
这就是她们悲惨又下流的原因
But you, you got a big life ahead of you, I'm sure.
但是你，你的人生一定会很精彩
Okay. I'm not a real secretary.
好吧 我不是真正的秘书
No, you're not.
对，你不是
- 'Cause you're smart. - Mm.
- 因为你很聪明 - 嗯
And you're curious, aren't you?
你很有好奇心，是吗？
Mm, I never really did very good in school,
我的学习成绩一直不太好
so I'm just kind of average, I think.
所以我觉得我只是个普通人
Oh, don't say that, Eileen.
别这么说 艾琳
- Never say that. Do you...?
- 千万别这么说 你...？
You really think you're a normal person?
你真以为自己是个正常人？
Normal how?
正常什么？
I really am a bad hostess.
我真是个不称职的女主人
Maybe we'll, uh...
也许我们...
We'll feel better if we eat something.
吃点东西会好受些
I feel fine.
我感觉很好
Can I use your bathroom?
我能用一下你的卫生间吗？
Sure.
当然
Just up the stairs.
就在楼上
♪ In the moments we shared
♪ 在我们相处的时刻
♪ You once said you cared...
♪ 你曾经说过你关心...
It's the other door, on the right.
是另一扇门，在右边
♪ I'm lost
♪ 我迷失在
♪ In the memory of you...
♪ 想你的记忆里...
♪ That so often I heard
♪ 我常常听到
♪ Are lost
♪ 迷失在
♪ In the memory...
♪ 在记忆...
♪ Are lost
♪ 迷失在
♪ In the memory
♪ 在想你的
♪ Of you
♪ 记忆里
♪ Our plans...
♪ 我们的计划
♪ Were all so sincere
♪ 都是如此真诚
Sorry.
对不起
What do you have to be sorry for?
你有什么好对不起的？
Go on. Go on. Eat. Eat. Yeah.
继续 吃吧 吃吧
Have a pickle, too.
也吃点泡菜吧
Why do we need a little, uh, cheese knife
为什么我们需要一把奶酪刀
To keep our hands clean?
让我们的手保持干净？
No. It's all ridiculous.
不，这太荒谬了
Everything is.
一切都是
All these stupid traditions,
所有这些愚蠢的传统
like the-the warden and his prison at Christmas.
就像圣诞节的典狱长和他的监狱
What do you mean?
什么意思？
I've tried explaining how things need to change,
我试着解释需要如何改变
but all he cares about
但他关心的
is whether or not the boys are gonna think about me
只是男孩们是不是会想起我
while they molest themselves in their cells at night.
当他们晚上在牢房里自慰的时候
God forbid.
上帝保佑
There's a strict
摩尔黑德有严格的
no masturbation policy at Moorehead.
禁止手淫的政策
It's illegal to get off in prison.
在监狱里爽一把是违法的
You know that, right?
你知道的，对吧？
As if that's the downfall of civilization,
好像这就是文明的堕落
people having orgasms.
人们高潮了
You can't count on men to fix anything.
你不能指望男人来解决任何问题
People are so ashamed of their desires,
人们为自己的欲望感到羞耻
especially men.
尤其是男人
Eileen...
艾琳...
as you can probably tell by now,
你现在可能已经知道了
I live a little differently than most people.
我的生活方式与大多数人有些不同
No, your house i-is nice.
不，你的房子很好
- No. - It's cozy.
- 不，很舒适
I don't mean the house. I mean...
我不是说房子 我是说...
I have my own ideas.
我有自己的想法
Maybe you and I share some of those ideas.
也许你我都有这样的想法
What kind of ideas do we share?
我们分享什么样的想法？
May I confide in you?
我能向你倾诉吗？
Of course.
当然
It's about Lee Polk.
是关于李·波尔克的
- It is? - Yes.
- 是这样吗？- 是的
Tell me, honey...
告诉我，亲爱的...
what would make a person want to kill their father?
是什么让一个人想要杀死自己的父亲？
Everybody wants to kill their father.
每个人都想杀死自己的父亲
No, they don't. Who told you that?
不 他们没有 谁告诉你的？
Really, think about it, Eileen.
真的，好好想想吧，艾琳
Because Lee snuck into his parents' bedroom
因为李偷偷溜进了父母的卧室
in the middle of the night...
在半夜...
hacked through his father's throat
砍断了他父亲的喉咙
with an old kitchen knife,
用一把旧菜刀
and stabbed him in the chest repeatedly.
并多次刺中他的胸部
His mother claimed she thought there'd been a break-in.
他的母亲声称，她以为有人闯入
How do you sleep through something like that?
你是怎么睡得着的？
I don't know.
我不知道
You don't. That's why I called her in.
你不可能知道 所以我才叫她来
I mean, you were there.
我是说，你当时在场
The poor boy could barely look at her, so...
这个可怜的孩子几乎不敢看她，所以...
so afterwards, I just asked him point-blank.
所以事后，我就直截了当地问他
I said...
我说...
I said, "What'd your father do to you?"
我说："你父亲对你做了什么？"
"What made you want to do that to your father's body?"
"是什么让你想这样对待你父亲的尸体?"
And he spilled it all in a matter of minutes.
他在短短几分钟内就全说了出来
Nobody had ever bothered to ask him before.
以前从来没有人问过他
No one had thought to ask.
没有人想过要问
Wouldn't you want to know?
你不想知道吗？
Wouldn't you be curious?
你难道不好奇吗？
Yes.
是的
Do you want to know?
你想知道吗？
Yes.
是的
Eileen, you can never tell anyone. Do you understand?
艾琳 你不能告诉任何人 你明白吗？
You understa... Promise me.
你明白...答应我
Promise.
我保证
♪ What happened to the love...
♪ 爱情怎么了...
The first thing you need to know,
你需要知道的第一件事
this isn't my house.
这不是我家
This is the Polk house.
这是波尔克家
I have Mrs. Polk tied up downstairs.
我把波克夫人绑在地下室了
Eileen. Eileen.
艾琳 艾琳
Eileen.
艾琳
Eileen, please wait.
艾琳，请稍候
Eileen, please.
艾琳，求你了
I thought I could do this alone, Eileen.
我以为我一个人就能搞定 艾琳
- Please don't go. Eileen!
- 请别走 艾琳
Please, don't go. Please.
求你了 别走 求你了
I thought you invited me over here 'cause you liked me.
我以为你邀请我来 是因为你喜欢我
Oh, I do.
哦, 我喜欢你
I do. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Please, Eileen.
我喜欢你 对不起 对不起 求你了 艾琳
Just pl-please, Eileen. Just give me a moment.
求你了 艾琳 给我点时间
Please just let me explain.
请听我解释
I need...
我需要...
I need a friend.
我需要一个朋友
I came here yesterday afternoon
昨天下午我来这里
to talk to Mrs. Polk.
找波尔克夫人谈谈
I said I could see that she was upset
我说我看得出她很难过
after our meeting with Lee,
在我们与李见面之后
was there anything she wanted to discuss.
她有什么想聊聊的吗？
She said, "Nothing", so I...
她说:"没什么", 于是我...
I pressed her.
我逼问她
I told her what Lee had told me.
我把李告诉我的话告诉了她
She spat at me, called me the pervert,
她朝我吐口水，说我是变态
then called her husband a saint,
然后称她的丈夫为圣人
and I left my card, told her to think about it.
我留下了名片，让她考虑一下
I knew she wouldn't call. Then I left.
我知道她不会打电话来 然后我就走了
Now, I couldn't sleep last night.
我昨晚一晚上没睡着
'Cause I...
因为我...
I couldn't stop thinking about what Lee had told me,
我一直在想李告诉我的话
what his father had done,
他父亲的所作所为
and how his mother had let it happen.
以及他的母亲是如何看着这一切发生的
I don't even remember the drive over here, I was so angry.
我甚至都不记得开车过来的路了，我太生气了
Suddenly I was pushing past her,
突然，我从她身边挤了过去
saying, "How could you do it?"
说："你怎么能这样做？"
"How could you be complicit in such torture?"
"你怎么能对这种虐待充耳不闻？"
And she snapped.
她大声叫骂
She attacked me. See?
她攻击我 看到了吗？
See?
看到了吗？
So I defended myself.
于是我开始自我防卫
We fought, and I... I don't know what happened,
我们打了一架，我...我不知道发生了什么
but somehow we fell down the stairs to the basement.
但不知怎的，我们从楼梯上摔到了地下室
I-I thought she was gonna kill me,
我以为她会杀了我
so I hit her with a chair and tied her up.
于是我用椅子砸她，把她绑起来
I tried to talk to her rationally,
我试着跟她理性地谈一谈
to explain that I was here to help Lee,
解释说我是来帮助李的
that-that I could help her, too, if she'd let me,
如果她愿意，我也可以帮助她
but... but she just kept screaming
但是...但是她只是不停地尖叫
that-that I'd kidnapped her and her husband was a cop
说我绑架了她，她丈夫是警察
and I was gonna go to jail.
我要去坐牢
So I found some codeine in a bathroom,
于是我在厕所里找到了一些可待因
and got her to be quiet.
并让她安静下来
Then I called you.
然后我给你打了电话
Because, as you can see, I'm in a bit of a pinch.
因为，如你所见，我正在紧要关头
What can I do?
我能做些什么？
I need Mrs. Polk to confess,
我需要波尔克夫人坦白
and I need a witness, two against one.
我需要一个证人，两个对一个
You understand?
你明白吗？
Oh, I can't go to jail.
哦，我不能进监狱
Okay.
好的
Wait here.
在这里等着
Eileen. Wait...
艾琳 等等...
It's incredible.
太不可思议了
Why do you have that?
为什么会有这个？
Why did you bring that around here?
你为什么把它带到这里来？
My dad's sick.
我爸爸病了
Pick it up, and show me how you're gonna hold it.
拿起来，让我看看你要怎么用
That's very good, Eileen.
很好，艾琳
All right.
好的
Be cool.
冷静一点
Just tell us the truth, Mrs. Polk,
告诉我们真相吧 波尔克夫人
and we'll let you go free.
我们就放你走
Families can heal.
家庭可以疗愈
You're not a lost cause. No one is.
你并没有迷失人性 没有人是
It can't have been easy,
这并不容易
being married to a man like that.
嫁给这样一个男人
You're obviously having a hard time.
很明显，你的日子也不好过
Why don't you tell us what happened in this house,
你为什么不告诉我们这房子里发生了什么？
why you helped your husband do what he did?
你为什么要帮你丈夫做这些事？
And then we'll be even,
然后我们就扯平了
and we can all walk out of here, and...
我们都可以走出这里，和...
we can figure out how to help Lee.
我们就能想办法帮助李了
Fucking untie me! Untie me!
他妈的给我松绑 给我松绑
Let me out of here!
让我出去
You crazy bitch, get out of my house!
你这个疯婆子，滚出我的房子
You're in big trouble, you think you're gonna
你有大麻烦了，你以为你会
- get away with this! - Eileen.
- 能逃过这一劫 - 艾琳
You're going to jail for a long time.
你会在监狱里蹲很长时间
What the hell is she doing here?!
她在这里干什么？
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
I really think you need to tell us the truth.
我真的觉得你需要告诉我们真相
What the hell are you talking about?!
你到底在说什么？
- If you don't...
- 如果你不...
we could leave you down here tied up,
我们可以把你绑在这里
no one to find you.
没人能找到你
The human body can't live very long
人体撑不了多久的
without food and water.
没有食物和水
Sooner or later, you're gonna need to take a shit.
迟早，你会需要拉屎
I guess you're just gonna have to shit yourself.
我想你就只能拉在身上了
And piss.
还有小便
It's not gonna feel very good.
感觉不会很好
I'm not scared of you.
我不怕你
I know you.
我认识你
I know who your dad is.
我知道你爸爸是谁
If you know my dad, then you oughta be scared.
如果你认识我爸爸，你应该感到害怕
Yeah? Scared of a womanizing, drunk piece of shit
是吗？害怕一个拈花惹草的酒鬼
who everybody knows is batshit crazy?
大家都知道的一个疯子？
You think he didn't have problems of his own?
你以为他自己没有问题吗？
You think he didn't have secrets of his own, huh?
你以为他没有自己的秘密吗？
You think your mom didn't know about 'em?
你以为你妈妈不知道吗？
Think it didn't...
认为没有...
I am going to fucking kill you
我要杀了你
if you don't start talking right now!
如果你现在不开始交代的话
Please!
求求你
Please, don't kill me.
求求你，别杀我
I won't have to kill you if you talk.
只要你开口，我就不会杀你
I can't.
我做不到
No, please.
不要 求你了
She's not gonna help you. Talk.
她不会帮你的 说吧
I can't help you unless you confess.
除非你坦白，否则我帮不了你
All right.
好吧
You win.
你赢了
When you get married
等你结了婚
and you have children...
有了孩子...
You take an oath when you get married
结婚时要宣誓
to honor and obey your husband.
尊敬并服从你的丈夫
You wouldn't understand that.
你们不会明白的
At first, I...
起初，我...
At first, I just, I thought Mitch
一开始，我以为米奇
was just checking on him in his sleep,
只是在他睡觉的时候看看他
you know, like any father would,
你知道，就像所有父亲一样
like he, he just wanted to be sure
他只是想确定
his son was safe and sound in bed.
他的儿子安然无恙地躺在床上
Sometimes I'd...
有时我...
feel him getting out of bed,
感觉到他下了床
and sometimes I'd just feel him when he'd come back.
有时他回来时，我就能感觉到
And he'd...
他...
kiss me or...
吻我或...
hold me and...
抱着我...
You know?
你知道吗？
And we hadn't really been together
我们并没有真正在一起
since Lee'd been born.
自从李出生以后
But then I...
但后来我...
I started getting these infections down there.
我下面开始感染
I figured it was my fault.
我想这是我的错
And then I wondered if Mitch
然后我在想，是不是米奇
had brought something home with him, you know?
他带了些东西回来，你知道吗？
Then one time...
然后有一次
I got up in the middle of the night.
我半夜起来
I don't remember why.
我不记得为什么了
Glass of water? I don't know.
一杯水？我不知道
I thought-I thought maybe it was a dream.
我想，我想这也许是个梦
I...
我
I went-I went and looked in.
我走了进去
It didn't dawn on me right away.
我并没有马上意识到这一点
You know, I-I swear to you. I...
我发誓
I mean...
我的意思是...
You don't expect your husband's
你不会指望你丈夫
gonna do something like that, you know?
会干出那种事来 你知道吗？
I mean, nobody would believe it, anyway.
我是说，反正没人会相信
And then I... and then...
然后我... 然后...
And then I figured...
然后我想...
And then I figured, if Lee was clean...
然后我想，如果李是干净的...
If he was clean,
如果他是干净的
an enema and a bath before bed...
睡前灌肠和洗澡...
then it would be better for all of us.
那么对我们大家都好
And it was.
的确如此
I knew what I was doing, it wasn't...
我知道我在做什么，这不是...
it wasn't quite right.
这不太对
I did know that. I did.
我知道 我知道
But who do you tell? You know?
但你会告诉谁呢？你知道吗？
Who could I tell?
我能告诉谁呢？
I mean, you do the best you can.
我的意思是，你要尽力而为
You know what happens when you have children?
你知道生了孩子之后会发生什么吗？
Your husband never looks at you the same.
你丈夫看你的眼神再也不一样了
But after he went to bed with Lee,
但在他和李上床之后
he'd come to me.
他会来找我
It was like a big burden had been lifted.
就像卸下了一个沉重的包袱
He was, he was relaxed.
他，他很放松
It felt good, how he'd hold me.
他抱着我的感觉真好
He loved me then.
那会他爱我
He would whisper and kiss me.
他会轻声地吻我
It was the way it had been before...
这就是以前的样子...
when we were young and happy and in love.
那时我们年轻 快乐 相爱
It felt good.
感觉很好
Is that so wrong...
这有什么不对吗...
to want to feel like that?
想拥有这种感觉？
You wouldn't understand.
你不会明白的
You're young, you haven't had your heart broken.
你还年轻，还没有心碎过
I'm bleeding! I'm bleeding!
我在流血 我在流血
Help me! Help me!
救救我 救救我
Please! Plea... Help me!
求你了 求...救救我
- I'm bleeding! - Shh! Shh!
- 我在流血 - 嘘
- Help me! You'll be sorry! - Eileen, help me!
- 救救我 你会后悔的 - 艾琳 帮我
I'll tell everyone what you've done!
我会告诉所有人你做了什么
- Eileen! - A doctor!
- 艾琳 - 医生
Get a doctor!
叫个医生
- Get me out of here! - Eileen, help me!
- 救我出去 - 艾琳 帮帮我
Help me!
救救我
No! No!
不要
No.
不
No! No!
不要
Okay. Okay.
好了 好了
Why did you shoot her?
你为什么开枪打她？
I was upset.
我太难受了
What do we do now?
我们现在该怎么办？
We take her to my house.
我们带她去我家
My dad's always whipping his gun out.
我爸爸总是把枪拿出来晃
Everyone knows it.
人人皆知
We can make it look like he shot her in a blackout.
我们可以伪装成他是在喝多后打死她的
He's just a drunk piece of shit, right?
他只是个酒鬼，对吧？
He's gonna die anyway or go crazy.
无论如何他都会死，或者疯掉
The doctor said so.
医生是这么说的
So let's take her together and leave.
我们带她一起走吧
Then we could go to New York for the New Year...
然后我们就可以去纽约过年了...
just the two of us.
只有我们两个人
I love you.
我爱你
It's okay.
没关系
Come on.
来吧
All right.
好吧
You go ahead to your father's house.
你先去你父亲家
Wait for me there.
在那儿等我
- Yeah. - I'll clean up inside.
- 好 - 我去里面收拾一下
We can't leave any evidence behind.
我们不能留下任何证据
- I'll be waiting. - I'll be quick.
- 我会等你的 - 我会很快的
Eileen.
艾琳
Go back to sleep, Dad.
继续睡吧，爸爸
Where you going?
你要去哪儿？
I might just get on the road.
我可能要上路了
All right, then.
那好吧
Good night.
晚安
《艾琳》